# Luke O'Hara

Location: Windsor Tel: 07710 282 449 Email: <a href="mailto:luke.c.ohara@gmail.com">luke.c.ohara@gmail.com</a>
Github: github.com/luke-c-ohara Website: www.lukeohara.com Linkedin: uk.linkedin.com/in/lukeohara/

### **Profile**

I'm a web developer looking for a new challenge in the tech industry having recently graduated from a coding bootcamp. My experience includes 4+ years in sales, working in professional environments, building relationships and working in a number of industries including finance, property and I.T. I'm looking for an opportunity to improve my development skills in a Junior Development position while applying previous client facing and business experience for an exciting company. The ideal position would be to work with a business which offers the right environment and guidance to further my coding skills while doing a great job for them in return.

## Experience

## General Assembly, London (Aug 2014 - Oct 2014) Web Developer Immersive course, Student

An intense 12 week bootcamp, covering a variety of different programming languages including HTML, CSS, Ruby/Ruby on Rails, Javascript, SQL, as well as learning areas of best practises, elements of computer science and how to code in a team. It also included agile development, Git and Github, Object Oriented Programming, REST, MVC and TDD.

**Project One** - A planning app for General Assembly, allowing people to create an account, book themselves on to courses, teachers to book classrooms etc using Rails, CanCanCan, Foundation.

**Project Two** - A wifi credentials storing app, allowing users to store details of wifi networks for when they are on different devices as well as sharing with friends using Rails, Javascript, AJAX, Googlemaps.

**Project Three** - A football statistics app, using a number of methods to pull data from online resources into one database, allowing manipulation of said data, focusing on Goals scored in Premiership games using Rails, Javascript, AJAX, CSV, Webscraping, Downspout.

# Alpha FX, Windsor, (Nov 2012 – Aug 2014) Foreign Currency Broker

Providing bespoke FX services to small and medium corporates through tailored market information, unmatched customer service and relationship building. Telephone, email, meeting correspondence with clients to discuss requirements. A full 360 sales role from sourcing leads, on-boarding process, closing accounts, account management. Adapting to varying levels of formality while pitching to high level MD/FDs as well as FCs/accountants for multimillion pound businesses. Using networking and relationships to not only gain contacts but to also become more visible throughout a business, especially when trying to promote services. Was very successful in a very difficult form of selling, cold calling financial services.

In addition to my primary selling role, taking on the responsibility for developing and maintaining Alpha's lead sourcing software (via Salesforce.com) as well as developing relationships/problem solving with internet, telephone and data service providers.

# Foxtons, London, (Oct 2010 – Oct 2012) Senior Lettings Negotiator

Selling to a range of high net worth individuals while providing a world class level of service to all parties in one of the fast moving lettings markets in the world. Quickly progressing to letting high-end properties all over East London. Seeking out and registering new clients, learning about people's requirements and working to meet them through a combination of phone and face to face scenarios. Learning creative selling and what really drives people in the buying process. Achieved while in a very high pressure sales environment while maintaining a 'people first' attitude to sales and customer service.

# IBM, London, (Jun 2008 – Sept 2009) Sales Administrator, Work Placement

Working alongside senior sales executives to provide a nationwide team, often based on client sites, with information on developments within sales accounts. Building relationships within IBM and with customers to gain information on products/services across the multiple brands within the company and how they could be applied to other businesses. Developing new processes for the companies annual Account Planning exercises using their internal software (eg Seibel). Developing new systems for monitoring progression of events (database, excel).

## **Education**

General Assembly - Web Development Immersive (12 weeks).

Bournemouth University - BA (Hons) Business Studies Degree.

Yeovil College - BTEC National in Business Studies (equivalent 3 A, A-Levels).

### **Interests**

Since becoming a part of the tech community I'm looking to involve myself in as many meet ups as I can to build my own personal network, attending LRUG (London Ruby Users Group) and Drinkabout to name a few. The openness and relaxed nature of meet ups really suits me as I enjoy meeting new people, learning about what they do and discovering if there is anything we can learn from each other. I'm also using a number of online courses and tutorials to continue my learning of the languages listed above as well as looking to develop news skills in popular languages such as Node.js, Angularjs and MongoDB. The life long learning aspect of this industry is of great appeal to me.

Outside of programming, I try to play football as often as I can and I also try to ski at least once a year. Having taught myself I need all the practice I can get.